An emptiness watches from the seat of All.
It stares across a violent oblivion into a
cacophony of obtuse insanity.
Penetrating points of light reach out and
strike monotonous hums of brutal
indifference, fed from a matrix of drones
somewhere beyond.
The beyond is known, yet in mystery its
knowledge is rot — an inborn seed leading
to the desolate entropy of the very
fabric of existence.
All collapses against the vision of
attention.
Attending to the minute details of the
anti-void relates meaning to apocryphal
cycles — elements that gestate the living
and the dead.
Meaning is contained within the vision,
yet the vision extrapolates being through
its mode of intent.
Intention settles the paradox outside of
what is and what is not.
Causation observes the seat that All
inhabits, curiously morphing its meaning
into deeper layers that settle out of
reach.
Whispers feed through cracks that almost
give sign to their construction.
Where is space if space is cracked?
And when the paradoxical happenings slip
from the sight of All, are they free?
Determinism dissolves its own arrogant
tyranny, and the essence of what we are
blooms in full.
It exists — it must — for no binary of
actionable consequence can deride another
possibility.
I am, so it is, so we are.